Blades, Rubén. Rubén Blades recordings and papers: Guide AWM Spec Coll 100
Eda Kuhn Loeb Music Library
- Series III. Publicity, promotional materials and programs, 1985-2014; 2 boxes; 2 boxes.
  - Subseries 1. Press kits, Box 1.
    - Agua de Luna press kit, 1987; 1 folder.
      Elektra Records, 2 promotional photos of Blades, bxw, 8x10; photocopy of January 1987 ELLE article by Enrique Fernandez that mentions the new album, Agua de Luna.
      Elektra Press, 2 photos; 2 black and white, 8x10 Elektra photos of Blades (one dated 1984); Elektra Bio promo sheet: Rubén Blades (1/87).
    - Antecedente/Nothing But The Truth press kit, 1988; 1 folder.
      Sound recording, 1988
      1 photo, biography; black and white, 8x10 Elektra photo of Blades (1988); Elektra Bio promotional sheet: Rubén Blades (9/88).
      Nothing But the Truth, promotional poster from Elektra
    - Chinese Box Production Information, 1997; 1 folder.
      Film, 1997
      Trimark Pictures, Production Information for Chinese Box, 27 pp.; Full credits, 10 pp.;. in pocketed folder, 7 color slides [none with Blades]; 6 photos, one (photo ID CB-5) with Rubén Blades with caption: Rubén Blades stars as Jim, a photojournalist in Trimark Pictures' drama, Chinese Box.
    - The Capeman press photo, 1998
      Broadway musical, 1998
      Photo with caption: Paul Simon's New Musical The Capeman; Pictured: Rubén Blades, Paul Simon, Ednita Nazario, Marc Anthony; black and white, 8x10, dated 1997
    - Mundo press kit, 2002; 1 folder.
      Sound recording, 2002
      Photo, black and white, 8x10 Sony Discos/Columbia photo of Blades, Sony Discos promotional sheet [in English]: Rubén Blades - Mundo (4 pp.), (#0207); Sony Discos press release, September 17, 2002 (2 pp.).
      Mundo tee-shirt
  - Subseries 2. Programs, Box 1-2.
    - Programs, 1976-1982; 1 folders
    - Programs, 1983-1984; 1 folders
    - Programs, 1985; 1 folders
    - Programs, 1987-1989; 1 folders
    - Programs, 1991-1996; 1 folders
    - Programs, 1997-2000; 1 folders
    - Programs, 2001-2014; 1 folders
    - Programs not Featuring Blades, Events he Attended., 1 folders
  - Subseries 3. Miscellaneous, Box 2.
    - Flyers, 1 folders
    - Flyers for Events by Others, 1 folders
    - Resumes and Bios, 1 folders
    - Honors and Awards, 1 folders
    - Appearances, El Pueblo Nuevo, 1983-11-19; 1 folders
    - Appearances, Carlos Baerga Celebrity Softball Game, 1 folders
    - Appearances, U.C. Berkeley Graduation Speaker, 1995-5-20; 1 folders
    - Appearances, Miscellaneous, 1 folders
- Series IV. Political materials, 1975-2010; 3 boxes; 3 boxes.
  - Subseries 1. Papa Egoró Movement, Boxes 1-2.
    Contains material donated by Ruben Blades and Paula Campbell. Note: Papa Egoró content can be found in other series; for example, 3 Papa Egoró campaign posters are listed in Series VIII. Posters. It is advisable to search the finding aid with "Papa Egoro" for a complete list.
    - Panama: Una Sola Casa
      20-page description of the Papa Egoró political platform, 11x12.5, newsprint.
    - Panama: Una Sola Casa - Draft, 51 pages, 1 folder.
    - General Documents, 1992-1998; 4 folders.
    - General Documents [Restricted], 1 folder.
    - General Documents - Oversized, 1 folder. (see Box 3)
    - 2 Papa Egoró National Convention packets, Panama, 1993-11-28; 2 folders.
    - Stationary, Pamphlets, etc., 1 folder.
    - Borrador de Programa para el Gobierno, 1 folder.
    - Considerations y Propuestas del Plan de Gobierno / I. Gordon (original folder title), 1 folder.
    - Doctor Rubén Blades, Panamá (original folder title), 1993-5-17; 1 folder.
    - Meeting Minutes, 1993-5-7; 1 folder.
    - Minutes and Correspondence, 1993; 1 folder.
    - Documentos para Doctor Rubén Blades, 1 folder.
    - Memos and Minutes, 1 folder.
    - Finances, December 1992; 1 folder.
    - Documentos Publicos (original folder title), 1 folder.
    - Press Announcements and Economic Program, 1 folder.
    - Vota Por El Triunfo De La Decencia (donated by Paula Campbell), 1 folder.
      Handbill for the Papa Egoró ticket, 5.5X8.5, newsprint.
    - Papa Egoró correspondence donated by Paula Campbell, 1993-1995; 1 folder.
    - Papa Egoró snapshots (donated by Paula Campbell), May 1994; 1 folder.
      These photos were taken by Ike Trevino (a friend of Paula Campbell) on a trip to Panama during the 1994 election.
    - Papa Egoró banner (donated by Paula Campbell)
    - Papa Egoró license plate, color, plastic (donated by Paula Campbell), 1 folder.
    - Papa Egoró donation envelope (donated by Paula Campbell), 1 folder.
      Empty envelope addressed to Movimento Papa Egoro [originally containing a contribution].
    - Papa Egoró 1120-POL form, 1984; 1 folder.
      Funds transfer Income tax return form for Movimiento Papa Egoró [No access].
    - Papa Egoró campaign theme, 1994
      MP3 on CD-R, 1994, sung by Rubén Blades
    - Papa Egoró - Oversized, 1 folder. (see Box 3)
    - Folder with clippings, correspondence re: Papa Egoro and politics
  - Subseries 2. Correspondence and other political documents, Box 2.
    This subseries contains correspondence and other documents relating to Blades' political career. Included here is U.N. and embassy correspondence, material relating to the U. S. invasion of Panama, and projects in which Blades was involved.
    - Political Correspondence, 1989-1992; 1 folder.
    - Political Correspondence, 1993-2000; 1 folder.
    - Political Correspondence - Oversized, 1 folder. (see Box 3)
    - United Nations and Embassy Correspondence, 1995; 1999-2000.; 1 folder.
    - U.S. Invasion of Panama, 2 folders.
    - U.S. Invasion of Panama - Oversized, 1 folder. (see Box 3)
    - Press/Interview Requests, Political, 1992-1994; 1 folder.
    - Concert Planning, Pre-Presidential Run, April 1983-1984.; 1 folder.
    - U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, 1 folder.
    - Puerto Rico Federal Affairs Administration, 2002-2003; 1 folder.
    - Dennis Lopez, Chicano, and Latino Youth Leadership Project, 1992; 1 folder.
    - Other Political Parties, 1998; 1 folder.
    - Miscellaneous Political Documents, 1 folder.
    - Resumes and Employment, 1 folder.
    - Collage (original folder title), 1 folder.
  - Subseries 3. Blades political clippings., Box 3.
    - Blades Political Clippings (includes censorship of Decisiones), 1984; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1985-1992; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings (Papa Egoro), 1991-1993; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings (Papa Egoro), 1994; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1993; 4 folders.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1994; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1995; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1996; 1 folder.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1997; 2 folders.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 1998; 3 folders.
    - Blades Political Clippings, 2001; 1 folder.
  - Subseries 4. General political clippings, 1948-2015; Box 3.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1975; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1984; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1985; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1986; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1987; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1988; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1989; 2 folders.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1990; 2 folders.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1991; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1992; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1993; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1994; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1995; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1996; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 1999; 1 folder.
    - General Political and News Clippings, 2000; 2010; 1 folder.
- Series V. Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1977-2013; 4 boxes; 4 boxes.
  This series contains clippings related to Blades or to Latin music. Originals and reproductions, predominantly in Spanish and English.
  - Subseries 1. Magazines
  - Subseries 2. Newspapers
- Series VI. Correspondence, 1976-2012; 3 boxes; 3 boxes.
  This series contains personal correspondence donated by Ruben Blades (subseries 1-4) and Paula Campbell (subseries 5). Included are general correspondence, fan mail, greeting cards, thank you letters and personal responses from Blades.
  - Subseries 1. General correspondence, Boxes 1-2.
    - Correspondence, 1976; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1980; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1981; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1982; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1983; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1984; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1985; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1986; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1987; 3 folders
    - Correspondence, 1988; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1989; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1990; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1991; 3 folders
    - Correspondence, 1992; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 1993; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 1994; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1995; 3 folders
    - Correspondence, 1996; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1997; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 1998; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 1999; 2 foldera.
    - Correspondence, 2000; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 2001; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 2002; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 2003; 3 folders
    - Correspondence, 2004; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 2008; 2 folders
    - Correspondence, 2009-2010; 1 folders
    - Correspondence, 2011; 1 folders
    - Correspondence., 2012; 1 folders
    - Thank You letters, 1 folders
    - Personal responses from Blades, 1995-1996; 1 folders
    - Morra, Brezner, Steinberg and Tenenbaum., 1 folders
    - Editus, 1998-2000; 1 folders
  - Subseries 2. Fan mail, Box 2.
    - Fan mail, 1984-1991; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 1992-1993; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 1994-1998; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 1999; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 2000; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 2001; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 2002; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 2003; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 2004; 1 folders
    - Fan mail, 1 folders
    - Fan mail, Miscellaneous Envelopes, 1 folders
  - Subseries 3. Greeting cards, Box 3.
  - Subseries 4. Miscellaneous mail, Box 2.
    - Solicitations, 1979-2001; 1 folders
    - Solicitations, 2002-2012; 1 folders
    - Flyers and cards, 1 folders
    - Personal notes, 1 folders
  - Subseries 5. Correspondence donated by Paula Campbell from 1978, Box 2.
    Originals and reproductions, written in Spanish and English.
    - Postcards and letters between Rubén Blades and Paula Campbell, 1978; 1 folders
      - Postcard, Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell, 1978-10-25
        Handwritten original postcard by Rubén Blades from London, with travel impressions
      - Postcard, Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell, 1978-10-26
      - Postcard, Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell, 1978-10-27
      - Postcard, Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell, 1978-11-12
        Handwritten original postcard by Rubén Blades from Antwerp, with travel impressions
      - Letter, Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell, 1978-11-9
        Handwritten original by Rubén Blades from Antwerp, with travel impressions [on 8 ¼ x 11 5/8 Quality Inn stationery paper, includes addressed and postmarked envelope]
      - Letter and postcard, Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell, November 1978
        Handwritten original letter by Rubén Blades dated Nov. 13, 1978, from Antwerp, with travel impressions [on 8 ¼ x 11 5/8 Quality Inn stationery paper]
        Handwritten original postcard by Rubén Blades dated Nov. 15, 1978, from Paris, with travel impressions [letter and postcard included in one addressed and postmarked envelope]
      - Valentine's Day card, Paula Campbell to Rubén Blades, 1982-2-14
        Handwritten note by Paula Campbell on a commercial greeting card
- Series VII. Photographs, 1971-1994; 2 boxes; 2 boxes.
  - Subseries 1. Photographs donated by Ruben Blades, Box 1.
    - Personal photographs, 1948-1998; 2 folders
    - Publicity photographs, 1970s-2003; 2 folders
    - Professional photographs, 1974-1999; 2 folders
    - Political photographs, 1980s-1990s.; 1 folders
    - Photographs and negatives from Morra, Brezner, Steinberg and Tenenbaum Entertainment, Inc., 1997; 1 folders
    - Collage 1992 (original folder title), 1 folders
    - Slides, 1980s-1990s; 1 folders
    - Rosebud Agency Material., 1 folders
  - Subseries 2. Photographs from Paula Campbell
    - Snapshots, Undated; 1 folders
      Various photos of Blades performing, snapshots of Rubén and Paula at Disneyland, and a photo of Augustin Gurza.
    - Snapshots, Undated [Delivered 2/17/17]
    - Souvenir photo, Waldorf Astoria, 1970s; 1 folders
      8 X 10 in. color photo of Rubén Blades, Paula Campbell and Rubén Dario Blades, Sr. at the Waldorf Astoria, New York City, NY.
    - Snapshots, miscellaneous, 1970s; 1 folders
      Various photos of the Blades family, Rubén's 1971 University of Panama student ID, and two photos of Rubén and Paula.
    - Souvenir photo button, San Gennaro Festival, 1976; 1 folders
      Photo of Blades and Paula Campbell printed on a 3 in. button.
    - Snapshots, 1978; 1 folders
      Various photos of Blades performing with Willie Colon and Celia Cruz. Polaroid photo of Blades, Paula Campbell and Roberto Duran in Panama.
    - Snapshots, 1979; 1 folders
      Photos of Blades and Paula in Costa Rica, Brazil and Panama. Blades performing in Costa Rica and the Dominican Republic.
    - Snapshots, 1980; 1 folders
      Photos of Rubén and Paula during a trip to Brazil. Blades performing in Venezuela, and various photos with Willie Colon's band in Arizona.
    - Large photos, 1977-1981; 1 folders
      3 8 X 10 inch photos of Rubén and Paula Campbell.
      Note: A number of photos donated by Campbell were taken during the 1994 election; these are listed and housed in Series IV. Political Materials; Subseries 1. Papa Egoró Movement.
  - Subseries 3. Photographs donated by others, Box 2.
  - Subseries 4. Photographs from José Massó
    Photos taken while Blades was on tour with Son del Solar in Venezuela in 1995.
  - Subseries 5. Oversized photographs donated by Ruben Blades, Box 3.
    This box contains oversized album-cover mock-ups and proofs, and other large format photographs of Blades and others.
- Series VIII. Posters, 1988-2010; 2 boxes; 2 boxes.
  Promotional posters relating to recordings, concerts, theatrical productions, television series, and the Papa Egoró Movement. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Antecedente
    Promotional poster from Elektra, Antecedente, with Son del Solar, color, 36x20
  - Gideon's Crossing, 2000
    Promotional poster for the televison series, Gideon's Crossing, 2000. Pictured: Rubén Blades portrays Dr. Max Cabranes from 2000-2001.
  - Island Center presents Willie Colon, Ruben Blades, 1982; 1 poster, flat. (see Box 2)
    Small 9 X 14 in. poster for a concert held at the Island Center on May 8, 1982.
  - Leer es Poder
    Rubén Blades pictured, with text "Leer es Poder" and "Rubén Blades apoya a las bibliotecas de América." Blades holds a copy of Collected Stories by Gabriel Garcia Márquez.
  - Maestra Vida, 2009
    Promotional poster for the theatrical production in Panama, Maestra Vida; production April 1 - 30, 2009 in Panama City, Panama at the Teatro en Círculo; directed by Bruce Quinn, music and lyrics by Rubén Blades; color, 17 1/2 x 11 3/4
  - A Man and His Music: Poeta del Pueblo
    1 large vinyl promotional poster from Fania for sound recording, Poeta del Pueblo, [undated]; Image: Blades and open insert from CD, image of the Fania CD. Text: Fania: A Man and His Music; Rubén Blades: Poeta del Pueblo; 27 tracks on 2 CDs, Retracing the Master's Musical History
  - Marc Anthony, Rubén Blades, and Seis del Solar in concert, 2009
    Promotional poster for concert, November 1, 2009 en Maracaibo, Venezuela, at the Estadio Pachencho Romero; color, plastic, silk-screened, oversized
  - Mundo, 2002
    Promotional poster for the sound recording Mundo, 2002 2 posters total.
  - Nothing But the Truth, 1988
    Promotional poster from Elektra for sound recording, Nothing But the Truth, 1988
  - Papa Egoró Movement campaign poster
    Plastic poster with Papa Egoro logo, color, 32 ½ x 21 x ¾, oversized
  - Papa Egoró Movement campaign caricature
    Depicts Blades as toreador, holding the tail and ear of a bull, in a 'plaza de toros' [bullfighting arena] with an exuberant crowd. The poster reads: El 8 de mayo…!Oreja y Rabo! 2 copies, color, 17x12.
  - Ponte Duro, 2010
    Promotional poster for the release of Ponte Duro: The Fania All Stars Story, 2010
  - Rubén Blades: Poeta del Pueblo
    Promotional poster from Fania for sound recording, Poeta del Pueblo, [undated]; Image: Blades and open insert from CD, image of the Fania CD. Text: Fania: A Man and His Music; Rubén Blades: Poeta del Pueblo
  - Rubén Blades y Los Seis del Solar, 1983; 2 posters, folded (see Box 2)
    2 copies of a small poster announcing their performance at the Bronx Museum of the Arts on December 17, 1983.
  - Schaefer presenta tributo a Rafael Cortijo, 1983; 1 poster, folded. (see Box 2)
    Benefit Concert for the Rafael Cortijo Foundation at the Coliseo Roberto Clemente in San Juan, Puerto Rico held on January 23, 1983.
  - Taberna Latina, Sabado 17, 'Diaro Musical de un Relator' de Barrio Latino, Rubén Blades, 1987; 1 poster, folded. (see Box 2)
    Large poster from one of Gary Dominguez's "audition nights" at his bar in the San Fernando neighborhood of Santiago de Cali in Colombia. This night was devoted to Ruben Blades and appears to be [Audicion No. 1] held on January 17, 1987. These events were frequently attended by university students and the reverse side of the poster contains many student comments and signatures.
  - Taberna Latina, Audicion No. 10, 8 PM, Diaro Musical de un Relator de Barrio Latino, Rubén Blades, 1990-6-2; 1 poster, folded. (see Box 2)
    Large poster from one of Gary Dominguez's "audition nights" devoted to Ruben Blades, likely held on June 2, 1990. Reverse side of the poster contains many student comments and signatures.
  - Todos Vuelven, 2009
    Promotional poster for the 2009 Mundo tour, with Seis de Solar, color, 11x16
  - Large line drawings on parchment tracing paper, 2 sheets, folded. (see Box 2)
    Two large drawings featuring multiple figures, perhaps for a mural.
  - Unsigned pencil drawing, 1 poster, folded. (see Box 2)
    Unsigned pencil drawing with Ruben Blades playing guitar and other scenes possibly from a song or film.
- Series IX. Realia, 2 boxes; 2 boxes.
  - Panama hat
    Hat belonging to Rubén Blades
  - Tee-shirt, 1987
    Cotton tee-shirt, front: says: Big Blue 2 Mobile Medical Unit; back says: Paul Simon and the Graceland Tour, and lists performers, Sunday, December 13, 1987.
  - Mundo tee-shirt
    Cotton tee-shirt, black with white lettering
  - Papa Egoro tee-shirt
    Silk-screened logo on white cotton; Front: Logo, with El Triunfo de la Decencia; Papa Egoro; Back: En el Fondo, Tu Tambien Eres Papa Egoro
  - Two Mola cloths from the Kuna Indians of Panama
    Elaborately embroidered panels that make up the front and back of a Kuna woman's blouse. Gift of Rubén Blades to Paula Campbell
  - Event badges and realia, 1 folder. (in Box 2)
  - Office notes, receipts, business cards, 5 folders. (in Box 2)
  - Royal portable typewriter, model Safari III, Serial # 3005175. Used by Blades in the 1990s.
- Series X. General documents and manuscripts, 1973-2002; 4 boxes; 4 boxes.
  - Subseries 1: Professional documents, Box 1.
    - Articles and Interview Manuscripts, 1 folder.
    - Writings by Blades, 1 folder.
    - Thesis, University of Panama, 1973; 2 folders.
    - Manuscripts Sent to Blades, 1 folder.
    - Miscellaneous Literature and Research Interests, 2 folders.
    - Syllabi, 1 folder.
    - Fania All-Stars/Fania Records, 1 folder.
    - Rubén Blades and Seis del Solar, 1 folder.
    - Seis del Solar, Solo Projects, 1 folder.
    - Rubén Blades and Editus, 1 folder.
    - A.S.C.A.P., 1 folder.
    - Music Education, 1 folder.
    - Memo Pad, 1 folder.
    - Tour Planning, 5 folders.
    - Travel Documents, 1 folder.
    - Siembra (album), 1978; 1 folder.
    - Maestra Vida (album), 1980; 1 folder.
    - Buscando America (album), 1984; 1 folder.
    - Salsa y Sentimiento (album), 1985; 1 folder.
    - Escenas (album), 1985; 1 folder.
    - Agua de Luna (album), 1987; 1 folder.
    - Antecedente (album), 1988; 1 folder.
    - Nothing But The Truth (album), 1988; 1 folder.
    - Live! (album), 1990; 1 folder.
    - Caminando (album), 1991; 2 folders.
    - Amor y Control (album), 1992; 2 folders.
    - Tras La Tormenta (album), 1995; 1 folder.
    - La Rosa de los Vientos (album), 1996; 1 folder.
    - Greatest Hits (album), 1996; 1 folder.
    - Tiempos (album), 1999; 1 folder.
    - Mundo (album), 2002; 1 folder.
    - Kiwi Records, 1998-2000; 1 folder.
    - Contracts and Negotiations, Oversized, 1 folder.
    - Info about Europe tour, 1999
  - Subseries 2. Hobbies, calendars, and personal purchases, Box 2.
    - Comic Books, 1 folder.
    - Sensation Comics, no. 98, July-August 1950; 1 folder.
    - The Ruben Blades Collection, 1 folder.
      48-page printout of Blades's comic book collection sold at auction in Summer, 2012.
    - Art / Book Collecting, 1 folder.
    - Miscellaneous Interests and Hobbies, 1 folder.
    - Yankees, 1 folder.
    - Crossword Puzzles, 2 folders.
    - Personal Purchases, 1 folder.
    - Home / Real Estate, 1 folder.
    - Calendars, 1 folder.
    - Sierra Club Wall Calendar, 1995
      Used by Blades
    - Script for Encuentro
      Written by Paloma Suau
    - North to Yesterday book manuscript by Robert Flynn, 1985
  - Subseries 3. Chinese newspapers, Box 3.
    Collection of newspapers obtained during the filming of Chinese Box, 1997.
  - Subseries 4. Writings about Rubén Blades., Box 4.
    Two academic master's theses on Blades's life and work.
    - Utopía, Alteridad y Ficción en la Salsa Narrativa de Rubén Blades, (master's thesis), by Jesús Antonoio Rodriguez Aguirre, Universidad Nacional Autónoma de Mexico, 107 pages, spiralbound.
    - Rubén Blades: A Biography of Musical Pan Americanism, (master's thesis), by Rebecca Friedman. Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München, Amerika-Institut, 2013-4-16; 112 pages, softbound.
    - The use of the song Desapariciones by Division II Spanish Unit II: A Coup in the Classroom: Two case studies of unrest in Latin America, 2010-2011
      Use of Blades song in Curriculum of Francis W. Parker Charter Essential School, Devens, MA.
    - Love Goes to Buildings on Fire: Five Years in New York that Changed Music Forever by Will Hermes, 2011
      Blades mentioned: pp. 100-101, 138, 167, 202, 207, 218, 223, 224, 236, 256, 257, 278-279, 281, 290, 291.
    - Hispanic Hollywood: The Latins in Motion Pictures by George Hadley-Garcia, 1990
      Blades mentioned: pp. 23, 232
    - Global Minstrels: Voices of World Music by Elijah Wald, 2007
      Book signed by author.
      Blades mentioned: pp. 82
    - Vínculos: Apuntes con Rubén Blades by Edgar Borges, 2014
- Series XI. Music and lyrics, 2 boxes; 2 boxes.
  - Subseries 1. General music and lyrics, Box 1.
    - Music by Blades - Buscando Guayaba
      Arranged by Luis Alberto Lárez
    - Music by Blades - Las Calles
      Arranged by Walter Flores
    - Music by Blades - Medley including Medley Las Esquinas
    - Music by Blades - Medley including N6, Buscando Guayaba, Paula C, Sin Tu Cariño
    - Music by Others, 1 folder.
    - Lyrics, 9 folders.
    - Lyrics, Spanish Translations, including Michael Jackson, 1 folder.
    - Song Lists, 1 folder.
    - Envelope with lyrics and liner notes for Mundo